# Jim Reisner

# Software Engineer

7817 Gray Fox Dr NE Cedar Rapids, IA 52402 (319) 450-6639 jim.reisner@gmail.com

# **Career Summary**

An accomplished Software Engineer with solid programming and problem solving skills, specializing in Object Oriented architecture, Web Development, Analysis/Design, and Relational Database design. Skilled at finding the most practical solution to a problem, resulting in successful implementations in both team and individual projects

# **Technical Expertise**

#### Languages

C#, Typescript, Python, Javascript, Java

#### Web Technologies

React.js, ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET WebForms, jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS

#### **Databases**

SQL Server, Oracle, MySql, CosmosDb, Entity Framework, LINQ, SSIS

#### **Cloud & DevOps**

Azure Services (Azure Container Apps, Cosmos Db (Core API), Azure Functions, Service Bus, Azure Logic Apps, DevOps), Git, AWS, Docker

#### Concepts

Relational Database Design, Class Design, Integration, Enterprise Architecture, Microservices, RESTful Web Services, SOLID principles, Design Patterns, Cloud (Azure and AWS), Test-Driven Development, Agile

### **Experience**

RTX, Cedar Rapids, IA- Principal Specialist, Software Development 2021 - PRESENT

- Developed new applications using React.js, TypeScript, .NET, REST API
  - Integration with enterprise applications like SAP and Dynamics CRM
- Developed a custom log scanner tool that automated the analysis of multiple log files, identifying critical keywords and providing detailed resolution suggestions from a predefined database, significantly reducing troubleshooting time and improving system reliability
- Created deployment pipelines in Azure DevOps/yaml
- Enhanced and maintained legacy applications
  - ASP.Net MVC and classic ASP

#### Transamerica, Cedar Rapids, IA - Lead Software Engineer

2017 - 2021

- Designed Business Rule Execution Framework for sourcing data from various administration systems, executing business rules, and landing data into consumable Data Lake
  - Improved processing time from 12 hours to 20 minutes from previous solution
  - Introduced re-use of business rules, resulting in faster implementation of end-to-end processing
  - Created .NET Framework host to handle cross-cutting concerns like logging and error handling in a consistent, efficient manner
  - Created Python system to land data into Data Lake
  - Resulted in portable solution that could be executed on multiple cloud vendors or on-premises
- Designed, developed, and implemented a task execution framework for actuarial model execution, utilizing .NET Framework executing proprietary model execution software
- Designed and implemented a Python ETL platform for querying Hadoop data and landing in various destination systems.
- Utilized dependency injection to support unit testing and growth in framework capabilities
- Lead contract staff on solution implementations
- Mentored team members on Agile development methodologies

# Rockwell Collins, Cedar Rapids, IA- Senior Business Integration

Analyst

2013 - 2017

- Developed centralized web-based reporting application for Human Resources secured by HR roles
- Developed custom intranet applications based on ASP.NET MVC, jQuery and Bootstrap
- Created reusable automated data extraction from SAP system
- Mentored and shared technical knowledge with the team, specifically in enterprise development technologies

#### StoneRiver, Cedar Rapids, IA- Senior Programmer Analyst

2011 - 2013

- Designed, coded and tested solutions for the annual release of regulatory product
- Designed, planned, and implemented customized Team Foundation Server solutions to support Agile methodologies
- Developed Continuous Integration for multiple projects and teams utilizing CruiseControl.NET

#### Aegon USA Investment Management, Cedar Rapids, IA- Senior

Programmer Analyst

2005-2011

- Develop and maintain internal applications in .NET WebForms
- Standardized application code by implementing the Abstract Factory design pattern
- Developed reusable classes to retrieve data from an external third-party application
- Improved data processing by 80% through the use of SQL Server Integration Services

# **Personal Projects**

#### **Fretboard Magic**

October 2024 - Present

- Developed a full-stack music theory application with an instrument-agnostic backend API and guitar-focused frontend
- Frontend: React with TypeScript hosted on Azure Web Apps providing interactive visualization of music theory concepts
- Backend: .NET Core Web API hosted in Azure Container Apps delivering comprehensive music theory operations including scales, chords, and AI-powered musical insights
- Public API available at: <a href="https://fretboard-backend.orangerock-45925371.centralus.azurecont-ainerapps.io/index.html">https://fretboard-backend.orangerock-45925371.centralus.azurecont-ainerapps.io/index.html</a>
- Live application: <a href="https://fretboardmagic.azurewebsites.net/">https://fretboardmagic.azurewebsites.net/</a>

#### **News Notifier**

August 2024 - Present

- Utilizes Azure Container Apps, Cosmos Db (Core API), Azure Functions, Service Bus, Azure Logic Apps, Docker
- https://github.com/JimReisnerPublic/NewsNotification

#### **EDUCATION**

**University of Northern Iowa** - Finance

1992 - 1995

#### **Certifications**

Microsoft Certified: Azure AI Engineer Associate

Microsoft Certified: Azure Developer Associate

Microsoft Certified Solutions Developer App Builder

Microsoft Certified Professional Developing ASP.NET MVC Applications

Microsoft Specialist

Programming in HTML 5 with JavaScript and CSS3